Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Motion Pictures Documenting Men's Ice Hockey
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, motion pictures documenting men's ice hockey
1931-2001
RU 969
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
44.25
(93 items)
The records consist of motion picture films and videotapes documenting men's ice hockey at Yale.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Department of Athletics, 2004-2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Original motion picture films and videotapes may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies. If a use copy does not exist for a particular item, researchers should consult a reference archivist for policies and procedures governing the creation of use copies.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of motion picture films and videotapes documenting men's ice hockey at Yale.
College athletes; College sports; Hockey; Motion pictures (visual works); Videotapes; Yale University -- Hockey; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
- Men's ice hockey films, 1931-1969; Accession 2005-A-114
  Scope and Contents
  Arranged chronologically by season. All films are black and white, silent. Films #6-9 are short one reels, possibly of Tot Farrel. Films beginning in 1966 are sound film but can't confirm sound.
  - Harvard, 1931 February 28; film reel (16mm) (Box 1)
    - Duplicating master, computer files (DVD-Video)
      General note
      Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
    - Use copy, optical disk (DVD) (Box 1U)
  - Boston Hockey Club, 1931 January; film reel (16mm) (Box 2)
  - St. Mary's, Toronto, 1931; 2 (Box 3–4)
  - University Club of Boston & St. Nick's Hockey Club, 1931; film reel (16mm) (Box 5)
  - Princeton, 1938 January 22; film reel (16mm) (Box 6)
  - Harvard, 1938; film reel (16mm) (Box 7)
  - Clarkson, 1938; film reel (16mm) (Box 8)
  - Princeton, 1956 February; film reel (16mm) (Box 9)
    - Duplicating master, computer files (DVD-Video)
    - Use copy, optical disk (DVD) (Box 9U)
  - New Hamphsire, 1966 November 26; 6 (Box 30–35)
  - Cornell, 1966 December 10; 4 (Box 10–13)
  - Brown, 1967 February 08; 6 (Box 14–19)
  - Dartmouth, 1967 January 28; film reel (16mm) (Box 20)
  - Harvard, 1968 February 24; 3 (Box 21–23)
  - Colgate, 1968 November 30; film reel (16mm) (Box 24)
  - Harvard, 1969 March 1; 5 (Box 25–29)
- Men's ice hockey videotapes, circa 1979-2001; Accession 2006-A-230
  - Highlight footage of Bob Brooke '83, Minnesota North Stars versus Montreal Canadians, circa 1980s; 1 (Box 51)
    - Duplicating master, 6
    - Use copy, 1; optical disk (DVD) (Box 51U)
  - Harvard, Circa 1930s; 1 (Box 50)
    Includes footage of Yale player introductions. Original tape lists dates of 1931 and 1938. Includes inadvertent home movie baby footage.
    - Duplicating master, 7
    - Use copy, optical disk (DVD) (Box 50U)
  - Colby, 1996 November 24; videotape (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Denver, 1996 December 27; videotape (VHS) (Box 12)
  - Denver (Denver Cup), 1996 December 28; videotape (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Dartmouth, 1997 February 22; videotape (VHS) (Box 14)
  - Vermont, 1998 February 28; videotape (VHS) (Box 15)
    - Duplicating master, videotape (VHS) (Box 15D)
    - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 15U)
  - Princeton, 1998 December 4; videotape (VHS) (Box 16)
  - Wisconsin, 1998 December 27; videotape (VHS) (Box 17)
  - Colgate, 1999 January 29; videotape (VHS) (Box 19)
  - UNH, 2000 November 3; videotape (VHS) (Box 20)
  - Boston College, 2000 November 7; videotape (VHS) (Box 21)
  - St. Lawrence, 2000 November 10; videotape (VHS) (Box 22)
  - Clarkson, 2000 November 11; videotape (VHS) (Box 23)
  - Dartmouth, 2000 November 17
    - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 24U)
  - Vermont (Mac Sports Films & Videos, Waterbury, VT), 2000 November 18
    - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 25U)
  - Princeton, 2000 November 21; videotape (VHS) (Box 26)
  - Princeton, 2000 November 25; videotape (VHS) (Box 27)
  - Cornell, 2000 December 1; videotape (VHS) (Box 28)
  - Colgate, 2000 December 2; videotape (VHS) (Box 29)
  - RPI, 2000 December 8; videotape (VHS) (Box 30)
  - Union, 2000 December 9; videotape (VHS) (Box 31)
  - Michigan State, 2001 January 5; videotape (VHS) (Box 32)
  - Michigan State, 2001 January 6; videotape (VHS) (Box 33)
  - Brown, 2001 January 12; videotape (VHS) (Box 34)
  - Harvard, 2001 January 13; videotape (VHS) (Box 35)
  - Holy Cross, 2001 January 20; videotape (VHS) (Box 36)
  - Notre Dame, 2001 January 27; videotape (VHS) (Box 37)
  - Notre Dame, 2001 January 28; videotape (VHS) (Box 38)
  - Clarkson, 2001 February 2; videotape (VHS) (Box 39)
  - St. Lawrence, 2001 February 3; videotape (VHS) (Box 40)
  - Colgate, 2001 February 9; videotape (VHS) (Box 41)
  - Cornell, 2001 February 10; videotape (VHS) (Box 42)
  - Union, 2001 February 16; videotape (VHS) (Box 43)
  - RPI, 2001 February 17; videotape (VHS) (Box 44)
  - Vermont, 2001 February 23; videotape (VHS) (Box 45)
  - Dartmouth, 2001 February 24; videotape (VHS) (Box 46)
  - Harvard, 2001 March 2; 2 (Box 1–2)
    Content of tapes overlap. Tape 1 includes introduction through the second period. tape 2 begins in the middle of the first period and continues until the end of the game.
    - Duplicating master #1, 8
    - Use copy #1, 1 (Box 1U)
    - Duplicating master #2, 8
    - Use copy #2, 1 (Box 2U)
  - Brown, 2001 March 3; videotape (VHS) (Box 47)
  - Harvard (ECAC playoffs, 1st round), 2001 March 9; videotape (VHS) (Box 48)
  - Harvard, 2001 March 10; videotape (VHS) (Box 49)
  - Other hockey-related videotapes
    - Yale Hockey Association, undated; videotape (VHS) (Box 8)
    - Footage of NHL player Randy Wood (James Sportsfilm Services), videotape (1"), undated (Box 9)
    - ESPN2 hockey seedings, undated
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 10U)
    - 1988 Hockey, videotape (U-matic) (Box 3)
    - "Yale Hockey" working rough cut, 1988 December 16; videotape (VHS) (Box 5)
    - "Yale Hockey", 1988; videotape (VHS) (Box 6)
    - "Yale Hockey" recruiting video, 1988; videotape (VHS) (Box 7)
    - Murray Murdoch 90th Birthday Dinner, 1994 April 28; videotape (VHS) (Box 4)
    - Hobey Baker Finalists (Ray Giroux), 1998; videotape (VHS) (Box 18)
- Men's ice hockey films, 1976; Accession 2008-A-050
  - Princeton, 1976 February 3; 4 (Box 1–4)